Laura Greenstreet







कु

I am a PhD student at Cornell developing AI and optimization methods with sustainability applications. Previously, I worked with Dr. Claire Kremen to scale an analysis of functional connectivity to the global level and with Dr. Geoffrey Schiebinger to develop optimization methods for single-cell genomics.

EDUCATION -

2021 - Present Ph.D. Computer Science, Cornell University

Research areas: Deep Learning, Optimization, AI/ML for Science

2020 B.Sc. Honours Computer Science, Mathematics Minor,

University of British Columbia

PUBLICATIONS

- Greenstreet, L., A. Afanassiev, Y. Kijima, M. Heitz, S. Ichiguro, et al. DNA-GPS: A Theoretical Framework for Optics-Free Spatial Genomics and Synthesis of Current Methods. Cell Systems, 2023. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cels.2023.08.005
- 2023 Mirka, R., **L. Greenstreet**, M. Grimson, C.P. Gomes. A New Approach to Finding 2 x n Partially Spatially Balanced Latin Rectangles, CP, 2023.
- Brennan, A., R. Naidoo, **L. Greenstreet**, Z. Mehrabi, N. Ramankutty, C. Kremen. Functional Connectivity of the Worlds Protected Areas. Science, 2022. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.abl8974
- Greenstreet, L., N.J.A. Harvey, V. Sanches Portella. Efficient and Optimal Fixed-Time Regret with Two Experts. ALT, 2022. https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.2203.07577
- Zhang, S., A. Afanassiev, **L. Greenstreet**, T. Matsumoto, G. Schiebinger. *Optimal transport analysis reveals trajectories in steady-state systems*. PLOS Computational Biology, 2021. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1009466
- Li, H., J. Ezike, A. Afanassiev, L. Greenstreet, et al. Single Cell Analysis Elucidates the Maturation of Human Stem and Progenitor Cell Function from Fetal through Adult Hematopoiesis. Blood, 2021. https://doi.org/10.1182/blood-2021-151090
- Shahan R., C. Hsu, T.M. Nolan, B.J. Cole, I.W. Taylor, **L. Greenstreet**, et al. A single cell Arabidopsis root atlas reveals developmental trajectories in wild type and cell identity mutants. Developmental Cell, 2021. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.devcel.2022.01.008
- Massri, A.J., L. Greenstreet, A. Afanassiev, A. Berrio Escobar, G.M. Wray, G. Schiebinger, D.R. McClay. Developmental Single-cell transcriptomics in the Lytechinus variegatus Sea Urchin Embryo. Development, 2020. https://doi.org/10.1242/dev.198614

Workshops and Presentations -

- Greenstreet, L, J. Fan, F. Siqueira Pacheco, Y. Bai, M. Eichemberger Ummus, et al. Detecting Aquaculture with Deep Learning in a Low-Data Setting. SigKDD 2023 Fragile Earth Workshop.
- **Greenstreet, L**, and E. Lai. Developing a Data-Driven Electric Vehicle Strategy in Surrey, BC. SigKDD 2020 Social Impact Session.

Bioinformatics

Geospatial

Theory

Awards —	
2022-2024	Graduate Teaching Award x4, Department of Computer Science, Cornell University
2020	Undergraduate Summer Research Award , Natural Sciences and Engineering Research Council of Canada (NSERC)
2019	Data Science for Social Good Fellowship, UBC Data Science Institute
2018	Stanley M Grant Scholarship in Mathematics, UBC Department of Mathematics

Languages and Technologies -

3+ Years Experience: Python, Git, Linux

1-3 Years Experience: R, Julia, Matlab, Java, SQL

Libraries/Tools: Pytorch, scipy, Geopandas, cvxpy, sklearn, QGIS, Postgres, Gurobi, CPLEX

Experience: deep learning with geospatial data, contrastive learning, manifold learning, optimization, data processing for geospatial and single-cell sequencing data, SQL database development and integration

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE —

05/2023 - $01/2024$	Research Assistant, Computational Sustainability Lab, Department of Computer
05/2022 - $08/2022$	Science, Cornell University
05/2020 - 08/2021	Research Assistant, Schiebinger Lab, Department of Mathematics, University of British Columbia
09/2019 - 09/2020	Research Assistant, WoRCS Lab, Institute for Resources, Environment, and Sustainability, University of British Columbia
05/2019 - 08/2019	Fellow - Data Science for Social Good Program, University of British Columbia Data Science Institute

Work Experience —

09/2022 - 05/2023	Head Teaching Assistant, Cornell University, Ithaca, NY CS 2700 - Excursions in Computational Sustainability CS 4700/4701 - Foundations/Practicum in Artificial Intelligence
01/2024 - 05/2024 09/2021 - 05/2022	Teaching Assistant, Cornell University, Ithaca, NY CS 4220 - Numerical Analysis: Linear and Nonlinear Problems CS 3220 - Computational Mathematics for Computer Science
10/2021 - 11/2021	Database Consultant, City of Surrey, Vancouver BC
01/2019 - 05/2019	eTextbook Developer, University of British Columbia Library, Vancouver, BC
07/2015 - 08/2017	Information Technology Coordinator, Tilth Alliance, Seattle, WA

COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT —

2024	Organizer, AI for Science Seminar
2023	Organizer, NeurIPS Computational Sustainability Workshop
2023	Mentor, BURE Undergraduate Research Program, Cornell
2023-2024	Assistant Organizer, AI for Science Program, Cornell
2020-2021	Mentor, Data Science for Social Good Program, UBC Data Science Institute